XI YANG (IAN), AMRSC

Edinburgh ↑ +44 7840 076293 ↓ ian16yang@gmail.com ☑ www.linkedin.com/in/ianyangxi iii github.com/GrignardReagent



PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a self-disciplined and passionate MSc Bioinformatics student and MChem graduate at the University of Edinburgh. With extensive experience in the pharmaceutical industry, combined with ongoing specialisation in bioinformatics (fluency in 3 programming languages & Machine Learning techniques), I aim to leverage the power of AI and biomedical research to improve health outcomes.



EDUCATION

MSc Bioinformatics expected Distinction | University of Edinburgh, UK

SEPTEMBER 2023 - AUGUST 2024 (EXPECTED)

My 2 Master's degrees train me not only to understand practical Chemistry & Biology knowledge, but also developed my competency in programming and to apply computational skills in extracting valuable insights from high-throughput data. I am experienced with the collection & analysis of large datasets to produce high quality & comprehensive reports.

Computational Skills:

- ✓ Machine Learning: Proficient in using TensorFlow and Scikit-Learn for developing deep learning models e.g., LSTM/RNNs to analyse time series data, CNNs for computer vision; LLM for sentiment analysis to influence decision making; diffusion model for molecular generation; CUDA for HPC.
- ✓ UNIX Shell/Bash Scripting: Developed bioinformatics pipelines for automating sequence data quality check (fastqc), sequence alignment (bowtie2, samtools), genome coverage (bedtools multicov) and expression level calculations for high-throughput genomic data.
- ✓ Python: Practical use of various python libraries, e.g., Object-oriented Python, pandas, matplotlib to develop interactive bioinformatics programs to perform multiple sequence alignment (clustalo), conservation analysis (plotcon) and protein function prediction (patmatmotif, pepstats) of large datasets retrieved from biological databases e.g., NCBI;
- ✓ Website Development: Developed a modern, interactive drug discovery website to access large databases, to access OpenAI API and to visualise moleculeS, using Javascript, PHP, HTML and CSS
- ✓ Familiar Software/Platforms: Git, Conda, VSCode, Vim; Flare, AutoDock, rDock, PyMol, ChemDraw Awards:
- ✓ 2023 Community Prize: Recognition of my outstanding contribution to the School of Chemistry
- ✓ **Student Experience Grant:** Secured over £4500 to foster industry-academia collaborations
- ✓ 5 x Edinburgh Awards: Recognition of my involvement in a wide range of extracurricular activities

MChem (Hons) Medicinal & Biological Chemistry 2:1 degree | University of

Edinburgh, UK

SEPTEMBER 2018 – JULY 2023

IB & IGCSE | St Leonards School, St Andrews, UK

SEPTEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2017



RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

MSc Project Student Supervisor: Dr Antonia Mey | University of Edinburgh, UK

FEBRUARY 2024 - PRESENT

<u>Research topic:</u> Drug Discovery Strategies for Metallo ß-lactamase (MBL) using Diffusion Models for Molecular Generation

<u>Research Skills:</u> Independently & collaboratively scouted routes to identify research gaps and drafted research proposals

Self-Led Project Student Supervisor: Dr Antonia Mey | University of Edinburgh, UK SEPTEMBER 2020 – JUNE 2021

<u>Computer-Aided Drug Design:</u> Conducted a **molecular simulation & docking analysis** of the main protease of SARS-CoV-2 with a library of ligands using **Flare, AutoDock** and **rDock**.

<u>Teamwork:</u> Collaborated effectively with an interdisciplinary team of chemists and biologists, identified learning resources, trained each other, and organised workload to deliver maximum productivity. <u>Critical Thinking:</u> Using medicinal chemistry knowledge, interpreted and evaluated computational

results obtained to screen drug targets and candidates. Project Coordinator | School of Chemistry, University of Edinburgh

AUGUST 2023 - PRESENT

<u>Project Management:</u> Through frequent use of **Gantt charts**, led the development of a new student support model, effectively balanced academic commitments, anticipated and accommodated stakeholders' diverse schedules and consistently delivered project goals on time.

<u>Communication Skills:</u> Through effective communication strategy, collaboration with industrial & academic stakeholders and persuasive efforts with funding bodies, **secured over £4500** to offer 40 student site visits and spearheaded an unprecedented academia-industry collaboration.

<u>Leadership Skills:</u> Led and supported 10 student leaders to creatively problem-solve and guide other students, facilitating teambuilding and peer mentorship.

<u>Website Development:</u> Designed and developed an interactive website for student support resource management using HTML, Javascript and CSS, increased student engagement by 2800%; competent use of git for version control and website hosting.

Process Development Chemist | Veranova, Edinburgh, UK

JULY 2022 - JULY 2023

Research Skills: Evaluated research landscape in a literature review to inform future work.

<u>Problem-Solving Skills:</u> Approached problems by investigating root causes & researching the relevant literature; operated, maintained and troubleshot technical issues with analytical equipment routinely. <u>Analytical Skills:</u> Routinely used <u>Excel formulas and macros</u> to accelerate the analysis of a large amount of experimental data to produce high-quality product quality profiles.

<u>Organisation Skills:</u> Routinely planned, assessed risks, and carried out work independently. Through careful planning, safely performed dangerous experiments on my own under time constrain.

<u>Good Manufacturing Practices:</u> Maintained data integrity and quality by consistent use of Electronic Lab Notebook to ensure accurate, complete, and legible documentation as per ALCOA+ principles.

<u>Communication Skills:</u> Concisely and accurately summarised project work in frequent technical reports and site-wise presentations to inform colleagues from non-scientific backgrounds.

<u>Sustainability:</u> Played a substantial role in 2 sustainability projects, resulting in the annual **cost reduction** of at least 230k litres of hazardous chemicals upon full implementation.

Scientific Writer | Edinburgh University Science (EUSci) Magazine

SEPTEMBER 2020 – SEPTEMBER 2021

<u>Science Communication:</u> Thoroughly researched to understand the science behind popular global issues such as plastic pollution, global warming, and ecological preservation; **presented 2 scientific articles** in plain and simple language to serve a non-scientific audience.



SKILLS, ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

Languages: Mandarin | English | French | Teochew | Cantonese

Interests: Event planning, singing, hiking and involvement in educational & technological communities.